http://www.awf.org/privacy-policy

Effective: May 25, 2018
African Wildlife Foundation (“AWF”) has the utmost respect for your privacy, and we know that you care how your information is used and shared. This Privacy Policy applies to www.awf.org and all associated subdomains, mobile applications and any online services to which this Privacy Policy links (collectively, the “Sites”). By visiting any of the Sites, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy. If you disagree with any of the terms herein, please immediately discontinue use of the Sites.
What Information We Collect
When you visit the Sites, AWF and its service providers may collect personal information that you provide, such as your name, address, email address, demographic and payment information. “Personal Information” is information that identifies you as an individual or relates to an identifiable person.
In addition, AWF and its service providers use a variety of techniques to gather other information about your use of the Sites, including, among other things, your IP address, browser type, mobile device type, content visited while on the Sites and the duration of your visit to the Sites. “Other Information” is any information that does not reveal your specific identity or does not directly relate to an individual.
If you submit any Personal Information relating to other people to us or to our service providers in connection with the Sites, you represent that you have the authority to do so and to permit us to use the information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
Why We Collect Information
To ensure Africa’s iconic wildlife and wild lands thrive in a modern Africa we need to have effective communication and fundraising activity with our supporters like you. By understanding more about how you engage with the information we provide, we can improve how we communicate the most important messages that you need to hear. Collecting personal information like email addresses or home addresses allows us to directly communicate with you in a timely manner, keeping you the most up-to-date on how you can help Africa’s iconic species. Collecting data also allows us to see which communication works in the most efficient way so we can allocate more funds into conservation.
How We Collect Information
AWF and its service providers collect Personal Information that you provide while using the Sites. For instance, AWF gathers information when you fill out forms on the Sites, including, for example, e-newsletter sign-up forms, donation forms, and advocacy-related forms. We may supplement the information we collect from you with information we collect from and about you from other online and offline sources, such as public databases, social media platforms and from people with whom you are friends or otherwise connected on social media platforms. For example, if you choose to connect your social media account to your Site account, certain Personal Information from your social media account will be shared with us. This may include Personal Information that is part of your profile or your friends’ profiles.
Our service providers and we may collect Other Information in a variety of ways, including:
We use “cookies” to help us monitor traffic and collect information about the use of the Sites. Cookies are pieces of data placed on your device when you visit the Sites that help us recognize you when you come back to the Sites, allowing us, for instance, to remember the email address and password you use when you log in on a specific device. AWF uses the aggregated information collected from cookies to measure the number of visits to the Sites, the average time spent on the Sites, the identity and number of pages viewed and to gather other traffic data and information that allows us to improve the Sites. We also use the information for security purposes, to facilitate navigation, to display information more effectively, and to personalize your experience while using the Sites. Cookies further allow us to select which of our content is most likely to appeal to you and display it while you are on the Sites.
AWF also uses a variety of third-party web and mobile app analytics and optimization services to improve the Sites and enhance the visitor experience. For example, the Sites use a web optimization platform that may use technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags, and scripts to analyze behavior, gather demographic information and improve site administration. The Sites do not use these services to collect any personally identifiable information not otherwise provided by you in using the Sites, and they do not track your browsing habits across other third-party websites on our behalf. For more information regarding these practices, please visit the privacy policy of our web analytics service by going to https://www.optimizely.com/privacy.
We also use Google Analytics, which uses cookies and other, similar technologies to collect information about Site use anonymously and report website trends, without identifying individual visitors. You can learn about Google’s practices by going to www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/, and opt out of them by downloading the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on, available at https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout.
Certain information is collected by most browsers or automatically through your devices, such as your Media Access Control (MAC) address, computer type (Windows or Macintosh), screen resolution, operating system name and version, device manufacturer and model, language and Internet browser type and version.
We may collect your IP address, which is a number that is automatically assigned to the computer that you are using by your Internet Service Provider. An IP address may be identified and logged automatically in our server log files whenever a user accesses the Sites, along with the time of the visit and the page(s) that were visited. This is a common practice and is done automatically by many websites, applications and other services. We use IP addresses for purposes such as calculating usage levels, helping diagnose server problems, and administering the Sites.
We may collect the physical location of your device by, for example, using satellite, cell phone tower or Wi-Fi signals. We may use your device’s physical location to provide you with personalized location-based services and content.
Information that you provide, such as your preferred means of communication, does not personally identify you unless it is combined with your Personal Information.
We may aggregate Personal Information. Aggregated information does not personally identify you or any other user of the Sites (for example, we may aggregate Personal Information to calculate the percentage of our users who have a particular telephone area code).
How We Protect Your Information
AWF uses Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology to provide you with the safest, most secure experience possible. SSL technology enables encryption of sensitive information, including login credentials, passwords, and credit card numbers, during your online transactions. All of the forms on our site are secured with SSL technology so your personal information stays safe and out of malicious hands.
How We Use Collected Information
AWF may use your Personal Information:
To send you information about AWF or AWF partners.
To personalize your interactions with AWF, such as to customize your web and email content based on your interests, send you requests to participate in events in your area and otherwise target content and communications to you.
To respond to inquiries and fulfill your requests, such as to process donations, renew your membership or send you information about a project, as well as to provide membership services.
To send administrative information to you, such as information regarding the Sites and changes to tour terms, conditions and policies.
To allow you to participate in sweepstakes, contests, and similar promotions and to administer these activities. Some of these activities have additional rules, which could contain additional information about how we use and disclose your Personal Information.
To facilitate social sharing functionality.
For our internal purposes, such as data analysis, audits, fraud monitoring, and prevention, developing new products and services, enhancing, improving or modifying the Sites, identifying usage trends, determining the effectiveness of our promotional campaigns and operating and expanding our activities.
AWF may conduct supporter and prospect research to identify shared interest and connections. If we conclude that you have the potential or interest in supporting AWF’s efforts at a higher level, we may collect additional publicly available information about you.
We may work with trusted third-party partners such as database screening companies to provide us with further information about our supporters. This information allows us to engage with you in a customized manner and approach those who will be most interested in supporting AWF. You can opt-out of your data being combined and analyzed for prospect research by contacting privacy@awf.org.
Your Personal Information may be disclosed:
To our partners, our approved vendors and their service providers. We do not rent, sell, or otherwise exchange constituent data for residents of the European Union for marketing purposes.
To our third-party service providers who provide services such as website hosting, data analysis, payment processing, information technology, and related infrastructure provision, customer service, email delivery, auditing, fulfillment, and other similar services. We do not undertake all of our processing activities ourselves, but we ensure that we have agreements with vendors and partners, and as part of that agreement the supplier agrees to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law.
By you, on message boards, chat, profile pages, blogs, and other services to which you are able to post information and materials. Please note that any information you post or disclose through these services will become public and may be available to users of the Sites and to the general public. We urge you to be very careful when deciding to disclose your Personal Information, or any other information, on the Sites.
To your friends associated with your social media account, to other website users and to your social media account provider, in connection with your social sharing activity, such as if you connect your social media account to your Site account or log-into your Site account from your social media account. By connecting your Site account and your social media account, you authorize us to share information with your social media account provider, friends associated with your social media account, and other website users, and you understand that the use of the information we share will be governed by the recipients’ privacy policies. If you do not want your Personal Information shared with other users or with your social media account provider, please do not connect your social media account with your Site account, and do not participate in social sharing on the Sites.
To a third party in the event of any reorganization, merger, sale, joint venture, assignment, transfer, or other disposition of all or any portion of our operations, assets or stock (including in connection with any bankruptcy or similar proceedings).
We may also use and disclose your Personal Information as we believe to be necessary or appropriate: (a) under applicable law, including laws outside your country of residence; (b) to comply with legal process; (c) to respond to requests from public and government authorities, including public and government authorities outside your country of residence; (d) to enforce our terms and conditions; (e) to protect our operations or those of any of our affiliates; (f) to protect our rights, privacy, safety or property, and/or that of our affiliates, you, or others; and (g) to allow us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain.
We may use and disclose Other Information for any purpose, except where we are required to do otherwise under applicable law. If we are required to treat Other Information as Personal Information under applicable law, then we may use it for all the purposes for which we use and disclose Personal Information. In some instances, we may combine Other Information with Personal Information. If we do, we will treat the combined information as Personal Information as long as it is combined.
How Long We Keep Your Information
We only keep your personal information on file for as long as is necessary to satisfy any reporting, accounting, or legal requirements. If you request to unsubscribe from any communication from AWF, such as email marketing materials, we will keep a record of any appropriate contact information to enable us to comply with your request to prevent any future communication from us.
How You Control Collection of Your Information
Set your web browser to inform you of when cookies are being set before a cookie is stored, refuse any request to set cookies and do not accept cookies from AWF. Erase all AWF cookies from your hard drive.
Do not provide your information when prompted by the Sites.
Please note, however, that if you choose to reject or erase cookies, your ability to navigate the Sites may be limited. Further, in the event you choose not to share information, AWF will be unable to respond to your request for AWF information, enter you in any sweepstakes or contests, facilitate advocacy actions or send online postcards.
How Can You Stop Receiving Communications from AWF?
If you would like to opt out of receiving content from AWF, you can:
Take the opportunity to opt out in links on the bottom of marketing emails AWF sends to you.
Please email us at privacy@awf.org or call us at +1 888 494 5354 and we would be happy to update your communication preferences.
Does AWF Collect Information from Children?
AWF does not knowingly collect personal information from anyone under the age of 13. The Sites are not directed at children under the age of 13. In the event that AWF learns that it has collected personal information from a child under age 13 without parental consent, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have collected any personal information from a child under 13, please contact us.
Donor Privacy Policy
AWF respects the privacy of all of our online and offline donors and takes the utmost measures to safeguard donors’ personal information.
When donors provide AWF with their name, address and any other personal data, AWF uses that information to keep them informed of program updates, news, events and funding needs. If at any time a donor chooses not to receive these communications, they may contact AWF at privacy@awf.org to have their communications preferences changed according to their wishes.
When you become an AWF donor, with the exception of donors residing in the European Union, certain information may be shared with third parties (e.g., other nonprofit organizations, marketers) whose information or services we think may be of interest to you. These third parties may wish to communicate with you by mail or share your information with others. We do not share donor email addresses. If you do not want the service provider to communicate with you or share your information, you may contact AWF at: privacy@awf.org.
AWF’s donor information is maintained on a secure database. Only authorized personnel have access to this information and only for appropriate business purposes.
All donation records are maintained according to the applicable standards of record retention in effect at the time of the donation. All records are maintained in secure locations. AWF only uses payment processing services that are compliant with Payment Card Industry Data Security Standards (PCI DDS). Payment information is never stored on AWF servers.
AWF reserves the right to use or disclose any information as needed to satisfy any law, regulation or legal request
Your Rights
Under data protection laws you have various rights over your personal data. You have the right to 1) Request access to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you; 2) You can request we correct any personal data we hold about you; 3) You have the right to request we erase your personal data. However, please note there may be circumstances we are legally required or entitled to retain it; 4) You may request to object to us processing your data under the legitimate interest condition. However, in some cases, we may demonstrate we have a compelling legitimate ground to process your information.
If you would like to exercise any of these rights, please contact us at privacy@awf.org. We will need to keep a copy of your name, postcode and email address in order to identify you within our databases and ensure we do not contact you in the ways that you have specified.
European Union Privacy Rights
In compliance with the data protection laws set forth by the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), you have various rights over your personal data. You have the right to 1) Request access to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you; 2) Request we correct any personal data we hold about you; 3) Request we erase your personal data. However, please note there may be circumstances we are legally required or entitled to retain it; 4) Object to us processing your data under the legitimate interest condition. However, in some cases, we may demonstrate we have a compelling legitimate ground to process your information.
If you would like to exercise any of these rights, please contact us at privacy@awf.org. We will need to keep a copy of your name, postcode, and email address in order to identify you within our databases and ensure we do not contact you in the ways that you have specified.  In the case that you are requesting a copy of your personal information, we will also require two forms of identification. Once we have received your information request and your identification, we will respond within one month.
In accordance with GDPR, AWF will seek your explicit consent to be contacted by us for marketing purposes and store a record of your consent in our databases.
Your California Privacy Rights
If you are a California resident, California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits you to request information about our disclosure of your personal information to third parties for those parties’ own direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please contact privacy@awf.org.
Third-Party Services
This Privacy Policy does not address, and we are not responsible for, the privacy, information, or other practices of any third parties, including any third party operating any site or service to which the Sites link. The inclusion of a link on the Sites does not imply endorsement of the linked site or service by us. In addition, we are not responsible for the information collection, use, disclosure, or security practices (including the data security practices) of other organizations, such as Facebook, Apple, Google, Microsoft, RIM, or any other app developer, app provider, social media platform provider, operating system provider, wireless service provider or device manufacturer.
Changes to this Privacy Policy
AWF may from time to time and at its discretion amend this Privacy Policy without notice to you. The “Effective Date” legend at the top of this page indicates when this Privacy Policy was last revised. Any changes to this Privacy Policy will become effective when we post the revised Privacy Policy on the Sites. Your continued use of the Sites following these changes means that you accept the revised Privacy Policy.
Security
We seek to use reasonable organizational, technical and administrative measures to protect Personal Information within our organization. Unfortunately, no data transmission or storage system can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. If you have reason to believe that your interaction with us is no longer secure, please immediately notify us in accordance with the “Questions/Contact Information” section below.
Cross-Border Transfer
The Sites are controlled and operated by us from the United States and are not intended to subject us to the laws or jurisdiction of any state, country or territory other than that of the United States. Your Personal Information may be stored and processed in any country where we have facilities or in which we engage service providers, and, by using the Sites, you consent to the transfer of information to countries outside of your country of residence, including the United States, which may have different data protection rules than those of your country.
We are part of a global network, and there are instances in which we may share your data within our Network. We may need to transfer your personal data to suppliers based in the US or other countries outside of the European Economic Area (EEA) to allow them to perform services on our behalf (such as when you sign up for a petition to help safeguard the natural environment). In doing so, your data may be stored or otherwise processed outside of the EEA.
Whenever we transfer your personal data out of the EEA, we ensure the utmost protection is afforded to it.
Questions
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please call 1-888-494-5354 to receive assistance from an AWF member services representative or email AWF at privacy@awf.org.
Unsubscribe
To unsubscribe from AWF's emails, please click here.
Wildlife need DOUBLE the protectionJoin Our Million Dollar Match by Dec. 20 and your gift will go 2X as far to save elephants.
DOUBLE YOUR GIFT
Webform: Homepage: Donate Form
Make a gift to protect Africa's most vulnerable species.
